Kaushik Mondal

Woodbridge, VA (Open to relocation) kaushikmondal1717@gmail.com

Software Engineer

PORTFOLIO: <u>kaushikm.com</u> <u>github.com/kaushikkm17</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/kaushikdev</u>

Software engineer with education in psychology and professional experience building full stack web apps using Python's Django/PostgreSQL stack and JavaScript's MERN stack. I also have experience with automated testing, CI/CD, and containerization. Previously worked in the mental health field from which I bring skills of communication and interpersonal skills, teamwork, research and data analysis.

Skills

Frontend: HTML/CSS, TypeScript, React, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Sass, Tailwind, JavaScript, EJS

Backend: Java, Python, Django, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Firebase **Devops:** Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins AWS S3 || **Testing:** Jest || **Version Control:** Git

Project Management: Agile, SDLC | OS: Linux, MacOS, Windows

Other: Photoshop, Figma, Trello, Slack, Visual Studio, CLI, Postman, Heroku

Work Experience

Software Engineer Apprentice, General Assembly

Nov. 2022 - Feb. 2023

- Created projects in a software engineering immersive program working 70+ hours each week for 12 weeks learning from industry professionals using the MERN stack and Django/PostgreSQL stack
 - Career Tracker Developed an app for job searchers that helps keep track of things like connections made, skills to learn, current tasks, etc. It is built using Django/PostgreSQL, styled with Tailwind, deployed to Heroku, and is able to authenticate and authorize users using Django's built in authentication.
 - **Techfolio** Collaborated with 3 other developers to build a platform for people in tech to display their technical portfolio including projects, skills, interests, etc. It used the MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, git team workflow, and Google Firebase for user login and is deployed on Heroku.
 - Cat Collector Developed an app where a user can add finches, their feeding schedule, and toys they play with using Django and PostgreSQL in a full CRUD app using Django for authentication and Amazon S3.
 - **Anime Generator** Created an app that displays an anime character or anime that retrieves the data from the Kitsu API and displays it to the DOM. Technologies used include jQuery, HTML, CSS, and Google Fonts.

Research Assistant, George Mason University Dept. of Psychology *Fairfax, VA*

Mar. 2020 - Oct. 2021

- Collaborated with fellow researchers to execute fMRI studies and meticulously analyzed the data obtained from participants
- Conducted extensive research, sourced and analyzed relevant articles, and effectively communicated findings to the lead researcher.
- Assisted in the study planning process by contributing to the development of methods, and provided thorough proofreading support for the final paper.

Education

Software Engineering Immersive Bootcamp, *General Assembly* **Bachelor of Science in Psychology,** *George Mason University*

Nov. 2022 - Feb. 2023

Sept. 2018 - May. 2022